卖报 卖报
Paper, paper.
成了
Finished.
华生 你对它有什么看法?
What do you make of it Watson?
嗯?
Huh?
我想你后脑勺上一定长眼睛了吧 福尔摩斯
I believe you got eyes in the back of your head Holmes.
我眼前放着一个擦得锃亮的咖啡壶
Well I have a well-polished coffee pot in front of me.
哈德森太太说是昨晚你出门时
Mrs. Hudson said it was left last night
有人落下的
while you were out.
你对它有什么看法?
What do you make of it?
我想
Well
至少我们知道了他的名字
his name at least we know.
我认为 摩梯末医生是一位功成名就
I think Dr. Mortimer is a successful,
年岁较大的杏林人士
elderly medical man,
受人尊敬
well esteemed,
认识他的人们送给他
since those who know him gave him
这件表示感激的纪念品
this mark of their appreciation.
没错
Yeah.
我还认为他是位乡村医生
I think he's a country practitioner,
出诊时大多是步行的
does a good deal of his visiting on foot.
'C.C.H.的朋友们'
'Friends of the C.C.H.'
我猜可能是当地的猎人会 (打猎的首字母为H)
I should guess that to be the local hunt.
哦好啊 好极了 华生
Oh bravo, bravo Watson.
你知道 我不能不说
You know I am bound to say
你已经习惯性地低估自己的能力了
you habitually underrate your abilities.
也许你本身并不能发光
It may be that you are not yourself luminous,
但你是光的传导者
but you are a conductor of light.
有些人本身并不是天才
Some people without possessing genius
却有着可观的激发天才的力量
have remarkable power for stimulating it.
我得说 我亲爱的伙伴
I confess, my dear fellow,
我真是太感谢你了
that I am very much in your debt.
谢谢
Thank you.
但是 我恐怕
But I'm afraid that
你的大多数结论都是错误的
most of your conclusions were erroneous.
'H'
'H'?
肯定指的是"医院" (医院也是H打头)
Surely hospital.
'C.C.'应该是查林十字会 (Charing Cross)
'C.C.' suggests Charing Cross.
在我的推理中 这是一个年轻人
I mean if so I would postulate a young man
不到三十岁 和蔼可亲
under thirty, amiable,
做事马马虎虎
absent-minded,
不追求功名
unambitious
还养了一条狗
and the possessor of a dog.
能给我看看手杖吗?
Can I see the stick?
谢谢
Thank you.
养的狗比梗犬大
Larger than a terrier,
比獒犬要小
smaller than a mastiff.
我是对的
I was right,
是一只卷毛的斯班尼犬
a curly haired spaniel.
摩梯末医生?
Dr. Mortimer?
太感谢您了 先生
Thank you sir.
谢谢您
Thank you.
我不敢肯定是把它落在了这里
I wasn't sure whether I left it here
还是忘在了轮渡公司
or at the shipping office.
S.S.直布罗陀号
The S. S. Gibraltar
今天到了特伯利的码头
you see docks today at Tewberry.
我对您很感兴趣 福尔摩斯先生
You interest me very much, Mr. Holmes.
我真想不到会看见如此长的头骨
I had hardly expected so dolichocephalic a skull
和这么深陷的眼窝
or such well-marked supra-orbital development.
您不反对我用手指
Would you have any objection to my running
沿着您的头顶骨缝摸一摸吧?
my finger along your parietal fissure?
得了吧 摩梯末医生
Please Dr. Mortimer.
在没有得到您头骨的实物之前 先生
A cast of your skull, sir,
如果能拥有它的模型该多好
until the original becomes available.
我并不想讨人厌
It is not my intention to be fulsome,
但我得承认 我实在很觊觎您的头骨
but I confess that I covet your skull.
您还是乖乖坐下吧 摩梯末医生
Behave and sit down Dr. Mortimer.
好孩子
Good boy.
好吧 我想您今天赏光来贝克街
Well I presume that it was not your phrenological passion,
恐怕不是为了研究我的头骨吧?
which drew you to Baker Street?
很可惜 确实不是
Unfortunately it was not sir.
斑斑
Spot.
我这里...
I have here...
我这里有一份传说的手稿
I have here the statement of a certain legend,
在巴斯克维尔家族流传着
which runs in the Baskerville family.
巴斯克维尔?
Baskerville?
是的 我是查尔斯・巴斯克维尔爵士的遗嘱执行人
Yeah, I'm an executor of Sir Charles Baskerville's will
这是在他的文件里发现的
and found it amongst his papers.
这件事关系到修果・巴斯克维尔
It concerns Hugo Baskerville;
他是个庄园主 也是达特姆尔高原上的恶棍
he was Lord of the manor, Grimpen on Dartmoor.
达特姆尔高原?
Dartmoor?
两百多年前的事了
Some 200 years ago.
这份文件的年代在那之后
The document is somewhat later.
"得知此事后
"Learn then from this story
将来定要小心慎行
to be circumspect in the future,
以免我们家族过去所尝到的深重痛苦
that those foul passions whereby
由于我们这些后代的败落
our family has suffered may not be loosed
而重新降临
again to our comparable ruin,
1742年11月8日"
8th of November 1742," was it?
这序言真吸引人 是不是?
Intriguing preamble.
我在报上看到过 查尔斯・巴斯克维尔爵士的死讯
I've read of Sir Charles Baskerville's death.
从医学角度来说
From a medical point of view
真没报道出什么内容
it was a poorly informed article.
不用了 谢谢
No thank you.
他死于呼吸困难和心脏衰竭
He died of dyspnea and cardiac exhaustion.
这两个症状是连锁出现的
Were the conditions linked
还是同时出现的?
or were they parallel?
依我看来 症状是连锁出现的
Oh they were linked in my opinion.
他的面部有些...有些扭曲变形
There was some, some facial distortion.
可以推测是心绞痛引起的吗?
Caused by the cardiac pain presumably?
可以
Yes.
听你的口气好像有点怀疑啊
You sound doubtful.
那面孔可不是一般的扭曲变形
It was not merely facial distortion.
这里写着 在1692年
Well here in 1692
修果・巴斯克维尔掳走了一个年轻姑娘
Hugo Baskerville abducted a young girl
但是她穿过沼泽逃了出去
but she escaped across the moor
在一个诅咒之夜
at night cursing.
他把犬舍里的狗都放出来去追她
He unkenneled his pack of hounds
就像狩猎一只小动物一样
and hunted her down like a wild animal.
当他那另三个醉醺醺的狐朋狗友赶到时
When his 3 drunken companions followed,
只见那姑娘已深陷沼泽
they found the girl in a deep dip or goyal
因为过度疲惫和惊恐而死
dead from fear and fatigue.
她丧命的原因是
And it also confronted the cause of her death,
一只巨大的恶魔般的猎犬
a huge, demonic hound.
他们目睹了
Even as they looked
猎犬撕扯着修果・巴斯克维尔的喉咙
the hound tore the throat out of Hugo Baskerville.
其中一个当晚就被吓死了
One companion died that very night of what he saw,
剩下的两个也被吓得精神失常
and the other twain were broken men
终身都成了废人
for the rest of their days.
这个传说从那时起便一直萦绕着这个家族
The sound is supposed to have haunted the family since then
不祥的气氛始终笼罩着他们
to the general misfortune of the line.
这个故事
Well this may appeal
倒是很对你那喜欢恐怖小说的胃口
to your lurid taste in fiction Watson.
这是个神话故事 先生
It's a fairy tale sir.
当然是的 福尔摩斯先生
Of course Mr. Holmes
但如果其中没有一点事实的话
but fairy tales would not survive
也不会流传这么久
without a kernel of truth.
查尔斯爵士死去的那天晚上
On the night Sir Charles died
我在刚点灯的时间 就到了巴斯克维尔庄园
I arrived at Baskerville Hall at first light.
我要告诉你们我所看见的
I shall tell you what I found.
绝无添减
No more or less.
这边走 先生
This way please sir?
我关注他的状况有一段时间了
I had been concerned about him for some time.
他对猎犬的传说
He had become obsessed
深信不疑
with the Legend of the Hound.
在凉亭那边
It's by the summerhouse.
他坚信他听到过
He believed he had heard
从沼泽传来的猎犬的吠声
the hound itself upon the moors,
他甚至坚信他看到过它
he even believed he had seen it.
当时我认为这些可怕的幻想
At the time I took such morbid fancies
正是查尔斯爵士
to be part and parcel
生理处于病态的部分表现
of Sir Charles' pathological condition.
而现在呢?
And now?
我绝不会那么认为了
I no longer believe that to be the case.
在那里 先生
There sir.
据我们所知没有人动过他 先生
We didn't like to move him sir. Once we knew.
好的 做得好 白瑞摩
Yes, Yes quite Barrymore.
这真是一场悲惨的意外 白瑞摩太太
A sad occasion Mrs. Barrymore
您一定彻夜未眠
an unhappy vigil for you.
他是我们的希望 医生
He was our hope doctor.
是这附近乡村所有人的希望
Hope for the country here about's.
他就是我们的全部世界
He brought the world to us.
是我们大家的希望
He was our hope.
在查尔斯爵士向小径跑去之前
Before Sir Charles ran up the alley
他就站在门前
he had eloquently stood at the gate
至少站了十分钟
for at least ten minutes.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
他抽的雪茄掉了两次烟灰
The ash had dropped twice from his cigar
而且那里还有3根用过的火柴
and there were also 3 spent matches.
您很出色 摩梯末医生
I'm impressed by Dr. Mortimer.
还有别的痕迹吗?
Was there anything else?
有
Yes.
莫非有脚印?
Footprints?
男人的还是女人的?
A man or a woman's?
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
是只特大型的猎犬的爪印
they were the footprints of a gigantic hound.
许多人都曾在沼泽见过那只怪物
Several people have seen a creature upon the moor,
是只巨型的怪物 狰狞可怕
a huge creature, ghastly, and spectral.
我盘问过两个声称见过它的人
I've crossed examined 2 of them.
都是脚踏实地的老实庄稼人
Hardheaded countrymen both
描述的情形也都和传说对得上
and their stories tally.
希望您能告诉我
I want you to advise me what I should do
亨利・巴斯克维尔爵士应该怎么办呢
with Sir Henry Baskerville.
亨利・巴斯克维尔爵士原先生活在美国
Henry Baskerville has spent his life in America.
他乘坐S.S.直布罗陀号到这里
He has come over on the S. S. Gibraltar
有您亨利爵士乘坐客船 我们不胜荣幸
Been a pleasure having you aboard Sir Henry.
亨利爵士
Sir Henry,
这头衔我听着还不太习惯呢
I still haven't gotten used to that title.
还有别人有权继承查尔斯爵士的遗产吗?
Was there any other claim upon Sir Charles' estate?
没有
None.
他最小的弟弟 罗杰
His youngest brother, Roger,
因为黄热病死于中非
died in Central America of yellow fever
三十多年前的事了
some 30 years ago.
亨利爵士是巴斯克维尔家族最后的子嗣
Sir Henry is the last of the Baskerville's.
当时您为什么没有马上请我去调查?
Why did you not consult me immediately?
有的问题 就连最精明老练的侦探
There's a realm in which the most accomplished
也是毫无办法的
detective is helpless sir.
有些事物
There are certain things here,
虽然全然不符合自然规律
which are impossible to reconcile
可依旧存在着
to the settled order of nature.
如果您认为这属于超自然的范畴
If you believe this to be supernatural
找个神父岂不是更好
you'll find more help from a priest.
不 不 不 不 不
No, No, No, No, No.
我怎样才能帮您呢?
How can I assist?
得给我个说法
And I'll have an answer damn it.
他正为靴子的事发火呢 先生
He's in a stir sir about his boot.
搞什么啊 如果找不到我的旧黑靴 就要他好看
By thunder if that fellow can't find my old black boot.
您丢的是一只新的棕色靴子吧
Surely it was a new brown boot.
不 昨天晚上他们把棕色的那双拿走了
No last night they took one of the brown ones.
今天他们又偷走了一只黑的
Today they've sneaked one of the black.
很抱歉 摩梯末医生
I'm sorry Mortimer
很抱歉为这些琐事麻烦你
I'm sorry to trouble you with this nonsense
可这还是所谓第一流的旅店啊!
but this is a first class hotel damn it!
哦 你好
Oh hello.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯为您效劳
Mr. Sherlock Holmes at your service.
我倒觉得这件事
I think it is worth troubling about
很值得讨论
as a matter of fact.
您何出此言?
You do why?
因为这件事不合常理
Because it's inexplicable.
好
Good.
很好
That's good.
老天
My God.
你感冒了么 华生?
Have you got a cold Watson?
都是这里污浊的空气闹的
Why it's this poisonous atmosphere.
我想这烟也确实够浓的了
This is a big thick I suppose.
浓?
Thick?
简直不能忍受
It's intolerable.
你一整天都待在俱乐部里吧
You've been at your club all day.
你怎么知道的?
How'd you know that?
你觉得我去了哪儿?
Where do you think I've been?
显然就待在这儿啊
Well here clearly.
显然?
Clearly?
我去了德文郡
I've been at Devonshire.
灵魂出窍?
In spirit?
正是
Quite so.
我派人从斯塔福德警局取来一份地图
I sent out for a map from Stamford's.
看到了么?
Now see here?
巴斯克维尔庄园
Baskerville Hall.
这里是格林盆村 只有几座零星散布的房屋
Grimpen, just a clutter of cottages.
这两间房在沼地上
2 moorland houses,
都是农舍
farmhouses,
赖福特庄园
Lafter Hall,
梅利琵宅邸 就这些了
Merripit House and that is all.
这些代表沼泽地区
Oh this represents marshland
这里就是
and these barrows,
曾经上演悲剧的舞台
some prehistoric settlement
或是埋葬的坟场
or burial ground.
10英里?
10 mile?
不用那么远
Disused is it
周围的一切都是多余
and all the rest is waste
我们那高明的罪犯
as far as the great convict,
最远也就只能到普林斯顿监狱了
the prison of Princeton.
这地方真是合适 如果魔鬼想要插足于人间之事的话...
It is a worthy setting if the devil did decide
这种想法也不是毫无道理
to dabble in the affairs of man.
这么说 你自己也倾向于
Then you yourself are inclined
神怪的说法了?
towards a supernatural explanation?
你最好给摩梯末医生捎个话
You'd better send word to Dr. Mortimer,
说我们明早和他共进早餐
we'll eat breakfast with him tomorrow.
这是今早寄来的
It arrived by post this morning.
对您来说是小菜一碟吧 福尔摩斯先生?
So you think of little puzzles Mr. Holmes?
它已经超过了我思考的能力
This one wants more thinking than I'm able to give it.
昨天寄出的?
Posted yesterday?
没错
Yes.
多半是玩笑吧
A joke, as like it's not.
亨利爵士 请告诉我
Tell me Sir Henry
您到了伦敦后 还遇到了什么奇特的事?
has anything interesting happened to you since you've been in London?
不 我想没有
No I don't think so.
有没有被人跟踪?
Ever been followed?
什么?
What?
好像我生活在离奇小说里似的
I seemed to have walked right into a dime novel.
为什么有人要跟踪我?
Why should anyone follow me?
这封信是寄到旅店来的
That letter was delivered to the hotel.
所以你确实被人跟踪了
You are being followed Sir Henry.
"若你珍视生命或还有理性的话
"If you value your life or your reason
远离沼泽地"
keep away from the moor. "
我在想的是...
The issue I suggest is whether it constitutes
这究竟是个善意的警告还是威胁
a friendly or an unfriendly warning.
显然不能确定啊
That is surely impossible to determine.
还是有一些线索的
However has features that may help,
比如说信封
the envelope for example.
如果说它有点被揉过还能见人的话
If somewhat trampled is presentable.
里面的东西就不是了
It's contents mostly are not.
这封信是被人
The letter has been torn
很仔细地从一份
neatly enough along a fold
泰晤士报的社论上剪下来的
and the leader article in the Times
绝对错不了
the Leaded Bourgeois printers,
肯定是从社论上剪下的字拼出的信息
unmistakable has been chosen from which to cut the message
但都是在匆忙之中剪下的
but the message is all quickly cut
用的是一把短刃的剪刀
with an appropriate short bladed scissors
而且在把这些铅字粘到纸上时
and the gluing of the print of the paper
弄出了不少污迹 也没有高低对齐
is smudged and misaligned.
给我看一下好吗?
May I see it?
这只是半张空白信纸
Only half a sheet of paper
水印依然清晰
and yet the watermark is clear.
哈德鲸鱼
Hudson whale.
这种纸在中等规格的旅店里
You will find that paper
都能找得到
in a hundred middle grade hotels
但这里不会有
but not from here.
上等旅舍提供的纸张会重一些
A first class hotel would have a paper of a greater weight.
这种墨水很常用
The ink is institutional.
也令我想到了是一家旅店
I would also suggest a hotel.
从中我们又能知道什么呢?
Yet what can we determine from this?
口袋里的棉絮
Pocket fluff.
我推断写下这封信的人
I infer that the person who wrote this message
就住在附近的某间旅店里
is staying at a nearby hotel.
他做事细致
He's neat of habit.
在这件事上也费了一番苦心
And studied the task methodically.
但他之后开始怕被人发现
But then he began to fear discovery.
在慌张中完成
He rushed it through
然后把信塞在口袋里
and put the result in his pocket
直到找到机会把它寄出去
until such time as he posted it.
诚然 有个可怕的人在威胁着你
It is true that fearful people threaten
但我的解释是
but my interpretation is
这是一封善意的警告
that this is a friendly warning.
因为似乎泄露出这个消息
Because it seems a risk was incurred
他也是在冒险
in its execution.
真是太棒了 福尔摩斯先生
Bravo Mr. Holmes
您果然是名不虚传
you fulfill your reputation sir no mistake,
但是 按您的说法 送这封信的人害怕的
but if you're right and this fellow's afraid
不只是他自己的问题
then he's afraid not only for his own skin
还在为我担心
but what might happen to me.
没错
Quite so.
摩梯末医生 我想现在应该您来解释了
Dr. Mortimer I think it is time that you explain.
现在您了解情况了 亨利爵士
Well now you know the facts Sir Henry.
问题就是
The question is whether or not
您究竟该不该到达特姆尔去
you should go to Dartmoor.
没有任何地狱里的魔鬼
There's no devil in hell
或是世人
nor no man on this earth
能阻止我回到我的家乡
that's going to prevent me from going to the home of my own people.
这样的话 我们就看看... 怎样把危险减到最低吧
Then we'll see how we can mitigate the danger.
您当真相信会有危险?
You really believe there is danger?
我想如果真有危险 就一定会出大事
I think that if it is, that it is considerable.
您一定不能单独行动
You certainly cannot go alone.
摩梯末医生和我一同回去
Dr. Mortimer returns with me.
他的诊所和家离你那儿还有几英里远
He has his practice and he lives some miles distant.
您能亲自去么?
You'll come yourself?
我得待在伦敦 有一桩勒索的案子
I have to stay in London, blackmail case.
我委托我的朋友华生前去
I recommend my friend Watson.
您真是太好了 医生
That's very kind of you Doctor.
我会的
I will.
-摩梯末医生... -谢谢你
Dr. Mortimer...Thank you.
华生!
Watson?
这边
This way.
那人是谁?
Who was that man?
我不知道
I have no idea.
你怎么知道
Well how did you know
有人在跟踪巴斯克维尔先生?
someone's been following Baskerville?
如果不是跟踪
How else did they know so immediately
他们怎么能立刻知道他住在哪?
where he was staying?
起码现在他们不会再跟踪他了
At least they'll not continue to follow him now.
华生 当危险到来的时候
When the crisis comes Watson,
肯定会到来的
and it will,
要向我报告
report to me.
华生 你知道查尔斯・巴斯克维尔爵士
Watson do you know what the residue
留下来的遗产有多少么?
of Sir Charles Baskerville's estate was?
我不知道
No I don't.
差不多一百万
Close to a million.
就是这人演这出危险大戏的赌注
A stake on which a man might play a dangerous game.
这可是很大一笔财富
Such a sum has a definite materiality.
不过现在 一切还都天差地远呢
And yet of all things in heaven and earth.
我们都是讲科学的人 福尔摩斯
We are men of science Holmes.
没错
Yet.
这可是桩邪恶又危险的案子 华生
It's an ugly, dangerous business Watson.
相信我 如果你能平安回到贝克街
Believe me I should be very glad
我会很高兴的
to have you back safe and sound in Baker Street Watson.
谢谢你 福尔摩斯
Thank you Holmes.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
我亲爱的华生 我不会说任何建议和怀疑
My dear Watson I will not bias your mind
来干扰你的思维
by suggesting theories or suspicions.
只要讲事实报告给我
Simply report facts to me
尽可能写得详细
in the fullest possible manner.
随后的日子里你得集中注意力
Concentrate your attention upon the following.
总之 一如古老的羊皮纸上写的那样
Above all, avoid the moor,
别在黑夜降临 罪恶势力嚣张之时
when as the old parchment frankly put it,
走过沼泽地
the paths of evil are exalted.
怎么回事 伯金斯?
What is this Perkins?
有个罪犯从普林斯顿监狱越狱了 先生
Convict, escaped from Princetown sir.
有三天了
Its 3 days now.
到处都在搜
They've been watching all over,
还没发现他的任何踪迹
they ain't seen no sign of him.
农户们都有些不安
Farmers don't like it.
逃出来的是谁?
Who is he?
塞尔丹 在诺丁山杀人的凶手
Selden, the Notting Hill murderer.
家家都门窗紧锁呢
Folk are locking their doors I can tell you.
这人干了什么?
What'd the man do?
他杀了一家人
He murdered a whole family
手段极其残忍
with such savagery they deemed him insane.
欢迎您 亨利爵士
Welcome Sir Henry.
欢迎来到巴斯克维尔庄园
Welcome to Baskerville Hall.
谢谢
Thank you.
你就是白瑞摩吧?
It's Barrymore yes?
听候您的吩咐 先生
At your service sir.
这是白瑞摩太太
Mrs. Barrymore.
太太你好
Madame.
只要有需要
If I can be of service
无论白天黑夜都尽管来找我
do not hesitate to send for me day or night.
当然 谢谢你
Of course, thank you.
走吧
Walk on.
这边请 亨利爵士
This way Sir Henry
我们家族的五百年历史
Five hundred years of us.
正如我想象中的
Just as I imagined it.
完全就和我想的一模一样
To much as I imagined it.
这地方需要放上些
This place needs the products
斯旺或是爱迪生的东西 (指两者发明的电灯)
of Mr's Swann and Edison
但我想我会适应的
but I suppose I can tone down to it.
谢谢
Thank you.
白瑞摩先生 晚餐非常美味
Excellent meal Barrymore.
请代我们谢谢白瑞摩太太
Please thank Mrs. Barrymore for us.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you sir.
您的喜欢一定会让她很高兴
She'll be pleased you enjoyed it.
华生医生 我们走吧?
Well Dr. Watson shall we?
先生...
Sir?
白瑞摩
Barrymore,
什么事?
what is it?
先生
Sir
我妻子和我都很乐意留在您身边
my wife and I will be happy to stay with you
直到你安顿下来
or till you've settled in
做出你自己的安排
and made your arrangements.
但是你的家族世代与我们在一起
But your family's been with us for generations.
如果我在这里开始的新生活
I'm sorry to start my life here
要打破这段悠久的往来 我会很遗憾的
breaking an old family connection.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you sir.
我妻子和我都很敬爱查尔斯爵士
My wife and I were much attached to Sir Charles
而他的故世
and his death.
我们觉得没有什么...
We feel that nothing can be...
我们觉得...
we feel...
继续留在这里 会使我们很不好受 先生
we feel we shall never be easy here at the hall sir.
的确
Right.
你们有何打算?
Well what do you mean to do?
由于查尔斯爵士的慷慨
Oh Sir Charles's generosity
给了我们一笔钱可以让我们
has given us the means to set up in business
做些小本买卖 先生
in a small way sir.
谢谢你告诉我这些
Well thank you for telling me.
我可以期待一下 某天在你家
Might I look forward to you pulling me a pint
得到你一杯美酒的招待吗?
in your own house one day?
这是当然了 先生 谢谢您 先生
That is the sort of thing sir thank you sir.
好
Good.
就这么约定了?
Mind you call it Baskerville arms?
好的 先生
Yes sir.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you sir.
这个男人害怕了
That man is frightened.
是的
Yes.
晚上不好捱啊
Turning into a rough night.
早上我要步行
I shall walk over to the post office
去格林盆的邮局
at Grimpen in the morning.
很抱歉 可是福尔摩斯嘱咐过我
I'm sorry but Holmes asked me
不能让您单独离开房子...
not to let you leave the house without...
医生 这玩意儿可以对付任何一条狗
Doctor, this shall take care of any dog
就算没有你的相陪
that I may meet in your absence.
就算你有武器
Even armed.
好吧
All right.
明天早上我会留在家里
Tomorrow morning shall find me at home.
在家总安全了吧?
I'm safe at home am I?
福尔摩斯是这么相信的
Well that's what Holmes believes.
这可是桩邪恶又危险的案子 华生
It's an ugly and dangerous business Watson.
相信我 如果你能平安回到贝克街
I shall be glad to have you back safe and sound
我会很高兴的
in Baker Street once more.
有的问题就连最精明老练的侦探也束手无策
There's a realm in which the most accomplished detective is helpless.
有些事物
There are certain things here,
虽然全然不符合自然规律
which are impossible to reconcile
可依旧存在着
to the settled order of nature.
总之 一如古老的羊皮纸上写的那样
Above all avoid the moor
别在黑夜降临 罪恶势力嚣张之时
whereas the old parchment quaintly puts it,
走进沼泽地
the powers of evil are exalted.
你知道查尔斯・巴斯克维尔爵士 留下来的遗产有多少么?
Do you know what the residue of Sir Charles Baskerville's estate was?
差不多一百万
Close to a million.
就是这人演这出危险大戏的赌注
Such a sum has such a distinctive materiality about it.
早上好
Good morning.
今天您好吗?
How are you today?
很好 谢谢
Oh very well thank you.
给你
There we are.
-谢谢 先生 -谢谢
-Thank you sir. -Thank you.
再见
Goodbye.
再见 先生
Goodbye sir.
华生医生?
Dr. Watson?
请饶恕我的冒昧推测
Excuse my presumption.
摩梯末医生在您经过他诊所窗前的时候
Dr. Mortimer pointed you out to me
把您指给了我看
from the window of his surgery as you passed.
或许他已经告诉你的名字
Possibly he's told you my name,
梅利琵宅邸的斯泰普顿
Stapleton of Merripit House.
是的 当然 您好
Yes indeed, how do you do?
我们都很担心
We were concerned,
弗兰克兰  摩梯末 和我
Frankland, Mortimer and I.
担心?
Concerned?
不太希望亨利爵士回来
Less Sir Henry should not have come.
你知道那个恶犬的传说
You know the legend of the fiend hound.
我们本以为这会让他噩梦缠身
We thought it might seize his imagination
就像可怜的查尔斯伯爵受到的影响一样
just as it seized poor Sir Charles's.
夏洛克 福尔摩斯先生还好吗?
How is Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
华生医生 您既然因此而来到此地
Dr. Watson you are here of it.
那么这一定引起了福尔摩斯先生的兴趣
It follows then that Mr. Holmes is interested.
我恐怕无法回答你的问题
I'm afraid I cannot answer your question.
请容我一问 我们有这个荣幸见到他吗?
Well may I ask if he is going to honor us with a visit himself?
他离不开城里
He cannot leave town.
有别的案子要忙
Other cases engage his attention.
你可以相信
I assure you
我来这只是单纯拜访我的朋友 亨利爵士
I'm simply here to visit my friend, Sir Henry.
我不需要帮助
I do not need help.
我为我的打扰道歉
I apologize for the intrusion.
沿着这条小径慢慢走
A moderate walk along this path
可以把我们带到梅利琵
brings us to Merripit House
或许您愿意抽出一个小时 华生医生
I wonder or perhaps you would spare me an hour Dr. Watson
让我有这个荣幸 把您介绍给我的妹妹认识
that I may have the pleasure of introducing you to my sister.
巴斯克维尔庄园的人还在等我回去
I'm expected back at Baskerville hall.
但是我想一个小时不会有大碍
I'm sure an hour will not hurt.
谢谢 斯泰普顿先生
Thank you Mr. Stapleton.
是因为对昆虫学的研究
It was entomology was it
让你走进这片沼泽吗?
that brought you to the moor?
的确 但是它本身也吸引了我
Indeed although I delight in it for it's own sake.
这里如此广阔
It is so vast,
如此荒凉
so barren,
如此神秘
so mysterious.
比如看那儿
Well there for instance
你有何感受?
what do you make of that?
是块少有的能纵马奔驰的地方
Well it would be a rare place for a gallop.
那就是伟大的格林盆泥沼
That is the great Grimpen Mire.
无论人畜 在那儿走错一步 就意味着死亡
False step down means death to man or beast.
昨天我还看到一匹小马驹闯进那里
Well only yesterday I saw one of the moor ponies wonder into it.
再也没有出来
Never came out.
过了很长时间我还看到它的脑袋
I could see his head for quite some time
从泥坑里探出来
straining out of the bog hole,
但最终还是被吞噬了
but it sucked him down at last.
就算是在旱季里 要穿越它也是很危险的
Even the dry season it is a danger to cross it,
而最近连续下了几场雨
but after these recent rains
它就成了一块不幸之地
it is an awful place.
然而
And yet
我可以找到一条直达它腹地的路
I can find my way to the very heart of it
再活着回来
and return alive.
但是你为什么想要去那么恐怖的地方呢?
But why should you wish to visit such a horrible place?
你看到那里低矮的小山了吗?
You see the low hills there beyond it?
它们是真正的岛屿
They're really islands.
那里的植物群与世隔绝
Flora there is undisturbed,
这就意味着
which mean of course,
会有稀有的物种生长在那里
that rare species can breed there
其中有一种兰凯尼迪的亚种
and one of them a subspecies Lycanidi
是这里特有的
is unique to the place.
事实上是我发现的它
In fact I'm credited with its discovery.
真的?
Really?
沼泽里到处是声响
The moor is full of noises.
但这是什么?
But what was it?
农夫说它是巴斯克维尔的猎犬
The peasants say it is the Hound of the Baskervilles
正在捕食
calling for its prey.
你不会相信这种无稽之谈吧?
You don't believe such nonsense surely?
你有听过鸬鹚叫吗?
Did you ever hear the boom of a bittern?
没有
No.
据说这种鸟眼下只有在
The bird is said, now, to be confined to
诺福克的沼泽里出没 但为什么这里就不能有呢?
certain Norfolk fens but why not here?
我听说它的叫声
I've heard its cry described
被描绘成介于
as being something between
尖锐的雾角和 灵魂的惨叫声之间
a foghorn and a soul in torment.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
啊...
Ah,
凯罗派德飞蛾
Cyclopides.
回去!
Go back!
马上就回伦敦!
Go straight to London instantly!
看在上帝的份上 照我说的做!
For God's sake do as I ask.
回去吧 再也不要踏入这里半步
Go back and never set foot on the moor again.
嘘 我哥哥回来了
Sh, my brother is coming.
斯泰普顿小姐
Miss Stapleton.
不惜一切代价离开这里
Get away from this place at all costs.
您看见那兰花了吗?
Do you see that orchid?
是 我看见了
Yes, yes I do.
真可惜您来晚了
It's a pity you came so late.
我们最好的兰花都已经凋谢了
Our best orchids are nearly over.
Jack
Jack.
我看见你已经自我介绍过了
You have introduced yourselves I see.
是的
Yes.
我正对亨利爵士说
I was telling Sir Henry
他错过了我们沼泽最美的风景
it's a pity he has missed the beauties of the moor.
如果我是亨利爵士 斯泰普顿小姐
Were I Sir Henry Miss Stapleton
我一定不会错过您的美丽
I'm sure I would not miss your beauty
可惜我不是
but I'm afraid I'm not,
亨利爵士是...
Sir Henry that is,
我算是他的朋友
merely his friend
约翰 华生医生愿意为您效劳
Doctor John Watson at your service.
你抓住你的蝴蝶了吗?
Did you catch your butterfly?
没有
No.
高山上的飞虫就像是巫女
Highly flies like a witch I'm afraid.
啊 在那儿
Ah there.
看这个
Look at this.
请您原谅并忘记
You must forgive and forget
我刚才愚蠢的鲁莽 华生医生
my foolish outburst Doctor Watson.
我忘不了 斯泰普顿小姐
I cannot forget Miss Stapleton.
您必须得忘
You must.
亨利爵士是我的朋友
Sir Henry is my friend.
我在乎他的安危
His welfare is a very close concern of mine.
告诉我你为何如此急于
Tell me why you are so eager
让他回伦敦?
that he should return to London?
你知道猎犬的故事吧?
You know the story of the hound?
我不相信这种无稽之谈
I do not believe such nonsense.
但是我信
But I do.
如果亨利爵士肯听您的
If you have any influence with Sir Henry
带他走吧
take him away.
恐怕除非你告诉我
I fear that unless you can give me
比这更可靠的理由
more definite information than this
否则是没法让他离开这儿的
it would be impossible to get him to move.
我说不出确切的理由
I cannot say anything definite
因为我不知道什么是确切的
for I do not know anything definite.
斯泰普顿小姐
Miss Stapleton,
我想再问你一个问题
I would ask you one more question,
如果仅仅如此而已
if you meant no more than this
为何刚才你向我开口的时候
when you first spoke to me,
如此焦急 而且不让你的哥哥
why were you so eager that your brother
听到你所说的话?
should not overhear what you said?
并没有什么是他
There is nothing to which he,
或是谁会反对的呀
or anybody else, could object.
我哥哥很希望庄园能有人居住
My brother is very anxious to have the hall inhabited.
他觉得这是件好事
He thinks it's for the good
对住在沼泽上的穷人来说
of the poor folk upon the moor.
他一定会生气
He would be very angry
如果让他知道我说了这些
if he knew I had said anything,
劝亨利爵士离开的话
which might induce Sir Henry to go away.
运气好吗?
Any luck?
恐怕没有
Afraid not.
飞虫就像是巫女 却如此美丽
Flies like a witch and so beautiful.
纹黄蝶
Pale, clouded yellow.
我已经抓住了不少
I have a number of them I've caught.
一定得给你看看我的收藏
I must show you my collection.
英格兰这块土地让我不再从医
The English led the Doctor out of my field.
我对那些昆虫已经做了特别的研究
And I've made a particular study of those insects,
它们栖息于石南和湿地的周边
which inhabit the margins of heath and marsh.
真是庞大的收藏
A magnificent collection
很有科学家的风范
and the work of a serious scientist.
甚至是那些奇特品种
Even the exotica,
我必须提一下这一神奇的物种 被称为莫普迪斯兰匹达
I must mention a brilliant creature called Morpo peridis lapida
被按照日期编制成目录
was dated and cataloged with the carrier replies
归入他个人的发现 英国兰凯尼迪蝶
to his personal field, the British Lycanidi.
它们正是这沼泽里独有的
One of which is unique to the moor.
我也要向你报告
I must also report
那只新的棕色靴子出现了
that the new brown boot has turned up.
Barrymore找到了它
Barrymore found it
就在他解开亨利先生的行礼时
amongst Sir Henry's luggage when he unpacked.
斯泰普顿小姐落落大方
Miss Stapleton is very handsome
星期二我们会在这里吃晚饭
and on Tuesday we are to dine here
同时邀请巴斯克维尔庄园的左邻右舍
at Baskerville Hall with all our neighbors.
于是 亨利爵士
So Sir Henry,
在受到你禁足令后终于喜上眉梢
who chaffs a little at the restrictions you have imposed upon him,
会有机会自己来评价对方美丽与否了
will have a chance to judge her beauty for himself.
我们也会和摩梯末医生的太太见面
We're also to meet Dr. Mortimer's wife
以及格林盆年长的牧师 他们说为人极其害羞
and the old vicar of Grimpen who is very shy they say
还有弗兰克兰
and Mr. Frankland,
算得上一名业余的天文学家
an amateur astronomer of some note
在人心目中是个得理不饶人的人
who has a reputation of being litigious to a fault.
这是个大喜的日子
A red-letter day.
法律就是法律 我得好好教教他们
The law is law and I need to teach them.
我被大家高高抬起
I have established a right-of-way
从老米德尔顿公园中央游行而过
slapped through the middle of old Middleton's Park.
今天宣判的结果
Case decided today.
我们必须教训教训那些混蛋
We must teach these magnets
他们不能冷酷无情地肆意践踏百姓的权利
they cannot ride roughshod over the rights of commoners.
今天宣判的结果
Case decided today.
今天 弗兰克兰先生?
Today Mr. Franklin?
今天 先生
Today sir.
你为什么问?
Why do you ask?
听说你在芬尼沃斯的森林
Seeing you in Fernworthy that you had the
要对村名关闭也是在今天
wood bear closed to the villagers also today.
所以我说了是个大喜的日子
Red-letter day as I said.
没错 先生
True sir.
今晚我的肖像又要被人在芬尼沃斯焚烧了
I shall be burnt in effigy tonight in Fernworthy
但是我有案子能告他们
but I have the case against them.
坏人被认为没有财产权
Infernal people seem to think there are no rights of property.
他们随意而居
They can swarm where they like
带着他们野餐的报纸和瓶子
with their picnic papers and bottles
他们还有什么好抱怨的?
but why should they complain?
现在没人去森林了
No one goes to the wood now.
他们必须穿过沼泽才能到那儿
They have to cross the moor to get to it;
没人会去穿越沼泽的
no one will cross the moor.
为什么呢 先生?
And why is that sir?
你肯定听说过了吧
You've surely heard?
猎犬在沼泽里出没
The hound walks abroad upon the moor.
巴斯克维尔的猎犬 亨利爵士
The hound of the Baskervilles Sir Henry.
我听说了
I've heard.
只有你一个人这么想吗 弗兰克兰先生?
Is it a phenomenon you believe in yourself Mr. Frankland.
问问牧师吧
Ask the vicar.
天文和法庭辩论是我的强项
Astronomic and forensic matters are my domain,
当地的事务是他的强项
demonic matters are his.
真有猎犬吗 牧师 还是别的什么?
Is it a hound of hell vicar or what?
是
Yes.
一个有趣的问题
An interesting question.
不管被看见的究竟是什么
Whatever it is that is being seen
它的确存在着
it is undoubtedly something.
我们的蹄铁匠 托马斯 查博
Our farrier, Thomas Chub,
并不是一个无中生有的人
is not a man given to visions
而他在那里看到了某种东西
and he saw something out there.
他说是一条狗
A dog he said,
个头有小牛那么大
about the size of a calf.
说当地人有些歇斯底里
And I do not think local hysteria
在我看来理由并不充分
is an adequate explanation myself.
不管它到底是什么
I pray nightly
我每天晚上都祈祷
that it remove itself
它能离开我们这个地方
from us whatever it is
让我们有更安稳的觉睡
and that we all may sleep the more soundly.
没错
Yes.
我觉得让大伙儿坐卧不安的
I believe it is Selden
应该是那个杀人犯塞尔丹
the murderer who frightens the folk.
格林盆一带的人都相信他仍在沼地里
In Grimpen they believe he is still upon the moor.
我们总是太富于优越感了
We are too ready to condescend and attribute
还总说这些可怜的人很迷信
superstition to these poor people
而事实上
when they are, in fact,
他们只是出于自然的本能的恐惧罢了
subject to a natural and sensible fear.
妙极了 斯泰普顿小姐
Bravo Miss Stapleton,
妙极了
Bravo.
这条恶犬是无法逃脱法律的惩罚的
This hellhound's existence
纯粹是乡间传闻
would not survive a court of law, mere hearsay.
把它带到法庭上
Bring the thing before the bench
经受法律的考验 我才会相信它真的存在
in the full blaze of jurisprudence say I then I will believe in it.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
谢谢你今晚的盛情款待
Thank you for a nice evening.
-晚安 医生 -很高兴见到你
-Goodnight Doctor. -Very nice to see you.
亨利爵士?
Sir Henry?
哎
Yes.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
亨利爵士
Sir Henry.
亲爱的朋友 今晚真是太好了
My dear fellow it's wonderful.
你的红葡萄酒真是不错
I must compliment you on that claret.
味道好极了
Delicious
真是太令人愉快了
Absolutely delightful.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安
Goodnight.
是白瑞摩吗?
Barrymore?
是的
Yes.
他在那儿呆了半个小时了
He's been there a half an hour.
他在干嘛?
What's he doing?
不知道
I don't know.
瞧!
Look!
在沼地上
Out on the moor.
事发偶然  亨利爵士
It just happened Sir Henry.
我们肯定不能再到沼地里去了
We must not go on to the moor undoubtless.
他们是不是有些夸大其词了 医生?
And then the powers are exalted Doctor?
妖怪是用来吓唬小孩的 老兄
Bogie's to frighten children man.
去吧 我们今晚有机会把事情查个水落石出
Come on, we have a chance of getting to the bottom of this business tonight.
在那儿
There.
华生
Watson.
怎么了 你还好吧?
what You all right?
我想开枪 可是开不了
I felt to shoot but I couldn't.
来吧
Come on.
天呐
My God.
你觉得这些传言可信吗?
You believe there's any truth in these rumors?
看呐!
Look!
那是什么?
What is it?
白瑞摩?
Barrymore?
无论如何不是塞尔丹
It's not Selden at any rate.
在伦敦我们就被跟踪了
We were followed in London
现在仍然受到跟踪
and we're followed still.
走吧 回屋子里去
Come on let's get back to the house.
到底怎么回事 白瑞摩?
What's this all about Barrymore?
先生 也许...
Sir it may...
也许看上去我们辜负了您的信任
it may seem that we have betrayed your trust.
看上去?
Seem?
见鬼 白瑞摩 根本就是!
Damn it Barrymore you have!
先生...先生 这不是他的错 先生
Sir...sir no fault of his sir.
他不想那样干的 都是我
He didn't want it it's me.
是我 是我的错
It's me and mine.
那个可怜人来向我求助 先生
The poor creature came to me for help sir.
我怎么忍心拒绝呢?
How could I refuse
看到他受了他们那么多罪
after what they have done to him?
白瑞摩太太 我不明白
So then Mrs. Barrymore I don't understand
他干嘛要来找你这样可敬的女士呢?
why should he come to respectable woman?
他是她的弟弟 先生
He's her brother sir.
什么?
What?
是真的 先生
It's true sir.
他到这儿来的时候饿得半死
He dragged himself here half starved.
你觉得我们还能怎么做呢?
And what would you expect?
我们给了他食物
We fed him.
我们把食物带出去给他 先生
We took food out for him sir,
就像您会对待一条狗那样
no more than you would for a dog.
我们希望他走掉
We hoped he'd go
但是夜复一夜那灯光都在那里闪烁着
but the light has been there night after night.
是真的吗 白瑞摩?
Is this true Barrymore?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
你知道那家伙干过什么吗 白瑞摩?
Have you any conception what this man did Barrymore?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
但他已经是一个没有伤害力的人了
But he's a broken man.
他们对他做了手术 驯服了他 先生
They done surgery sir to tame him.
他就像是个孩子 先生
He's like a child sir.
求您了 先生
Please sir.
白瑞摩太太 请你...
Mrs. Barrymore please.
请你起来
Please get up.
这样做有失尊严
This is not dignified please.
亲爱的
My dear.
先生 他已经被安排好离开这里
By a leave sir arrangements have been made.
几天后他就会离开这个国家
He'll be out of the country in a few days.
我恳求您 先生 别向警方举报他
I beg you sir say nothing to the police.
你觉得呢 医生?
What do you think Doctor?
你说他现在不会再害人了 白瑞摩
You say he's harmless now Barrymore
可是他还拿大石头砸我们
yet he threw a rock at us.
就像小孩子扔石头那样啊 先生
As a child might throw stones sir.
那些谋杀常常萦绕在他心里
The murders are going to haunt him.
他现在就像是个受了惊的孩子 先生
He's a frightening baby now sir.
这个形容很恰当
This is an apt description.
他不会再害人了
He will be harmless.
很好
Very well.
请把你的妻子带回房吧
Please take your wife to your room.
对这件事我们不会提起
We'll say nothing about this matter.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you sir.
我还以为我们得到了
I thought we had a chance
一个彻底查清此事的机会
of getting to the bottom of this business.
可是我们所做的 似乎只是犯下了重罪
All we've seemed to of done is compound a felony.
不过我还是很高兴
I'm glad though that you
你在沼地里听到了那个声音
heard that sound on the moor.
我原来已经开始觉得是我的幻听了
I was beginning to think I'd dreamt it.
我曾经去过保护区
I was in the territories once.
在那儿见到过不少狼
I've heard wolves up there
但是没有什么能像今晚的声音
but nothing to freeze the blood
那样让我毛骨悚然
Iike that sound tonight.
你确信就是那条恶犬吗?
Are you convinced it's the hound?
是的
I am.
我真希望福尔摩斯在这里
I wish to God Holmes was here.
他怎么还不来?
Why does he not come?
但是 福尔摩斯
And yet Holmes
当天亮了 小鸟又开始歌唱
when daylight and birdsong return
夜晚那种阴暗的景象荡然无存
the black imaginings of the night evaporate.
即使是摩梯末医生不断地拜访
Even Dr. Mortimer assiduous visits,
以及期间他不变的
accompanied as they are,
有关骨头和尸体的谈话
by constant talk of bones, or mortal residue,
也无法抹杀沼地秋日的美景
fail to sour the beauties of the moor in autumn.
可是 我们...
We are, however,
对于这个谜团依然毫无头绪
still far from the heart of the mystery.
而最让我烦恼的问题就是
The question, which most persistently nags me,
石山上的那个人究竟是谁?
is who's the man on the tor?
我觉得要是我们知道了他的身份
With his identity known
我们就能找到
I feel we should have the key
解开这个谜团的钥匙
to this fatal riddle within our grasp.
这块布料很好的
This is rather a nice piece of cloth.
我觉得...
I think they...
与此同时 我还发现了
Meanwhile, I have discovered a
我们的男主人心地非常善良
streak amiable tender heartedness in my host.
他对差点射杀男仆的那个杀人犯小舅子
So guilty did he feel of nearly shooting
深感内疚
his servant's murderous brother-in-law
于是他就给了白瑞摩
that he's given Barrymore
不少他从美国带来的做工一流的衣服
many of his excellent American clothes.
他决心当好
Determined, as he now is,
一个英国乡绅的角色
to play the role of English squire
不管是从服装还是从其他方面
in dress as in anything else.
太美国化了 而我正打算翻开生活崭新的一页
Much too American and I'm turning over a new leaf.
你拿去吧
You take it.
谢谢您的好意 爵士
Thank you kindly sir.
这衣服真不错啊  亨利爵士
Very smart Sir Henry.
是的
Yeah.
我打算散步去梅利琵庄园
Well I'm going to stroll up to Merripit House
我觉得我该邀请斯泰普顿和他妹妹
I thought I'd invite Stapleton and his sister
我更愿意说是斯泰普顿小姐和她哥哥
rather I should say, Miss Stapleton and her brother
星期一到我们这来用午餐
to luncheon on Monday.
好吧 我知道你不想要我跟你一起去
Well I know you won't want me to come with you there
可福尔摩斯坚持要我...
but Holmes insisted that I...
可是 我的朋友
Now look here my friend,
福尔摩斯不可能预见到某些事的发展
Holmes could not have foreseen certain developments.
你会成为一个很文明的电灯泡
You'd make a very civil gooseberry
我想我还是自己去就好了
but no I'm afraid I have to go alone.
下一站 伦敦
London next stop.
巴斯克维尔!
Baskerville!
巴斯克维尔 你怎么敢这样 先生
Baskerville how dare you sir
这样来占我妹妹的便宜!
make advances at my sister in such a fashion.
杰克!
Jack!
我肯定我妹妹并没有做什么事情
I'm sure the lady gave you no reason
让你误会了她的好意吧?
to presume upon her good intentions.
我们欢迎您加入我们的圈子 先生
We welcome you into our circle sir
而你却用这种让人厌恶的关心
and you repay the hospitality
来回报我们的热情
by forcing your disgusting attentions upon her.
不是的 我向你保证 先生
No but I assure you sir
-我的动机是纯洁高尚的 -滚吧 先生...滚回你老家去
-my intentions are honorable. -Away sir...away to the hall.
滚吧
Go on?
你好 华生
Hello Watson.
你是从哪儿冒出来的?
Where have you dropped from?
我跟踪了你
I took it upon myself to follow you.
我对福尔摩斯的承诺 比得体的行为更重要
I'm afraid my duty to Holmes overrode my tact.
我明白
I see.
希望在格林盆没有人卖票 (让大伙儿来看我出丑)
Well hope they're not selling tickets in Grimpen.
我想你都看到了?
I assume you saw what happened?
你觉不觉得这个当哥哥的
Did he ever strike you as a bit crazy
有些神经质?
this brother of hers?
不太觉得
Not particularly.
我不明白他怎么会对我这样
I don't know why he does me.
是什么让他这么激动?
What's he getting so heated about?
我当他的妹夫
What objection can he have
他有什么好反对的?
to me as a brother-in-law?
我是说他肯定不是反对我的身份
I mean he can't object to my worldly position
那么...他反对的就是我这个人了
so it's got to be me myself.
噢 我不明白
Oh I don't know.
你明白吗?
Do you see it?
不明白
Not at all.
我也是
Nor me.
谢谢
Well thanks.
他一刻也不许我们在一起
He won't let us be together not for a moment.
他应该意识到才对
He must realize.
她眼里有一种光芒
You know what I don't understand
胜过千言万语
there's a light in her eyes
我了解这种感觉...打心底里明白
that speaks louder than words.
可我不明白的是
I know it...I know it in my heart
他把我当成了一个...
but he treats me as if I was a...
一个闹剧里疯狂的色情骗子
if I was a mad seducer in an old melodrama.
真是够荒谬的
Oh it's absurd.
也许吧
Perhaps.
你说什么?
What?
我是在想
I was just thinking
有关这条猎犬事情
that this business with the hound
还有对这个家族的诅咒等等
and the family curse and so on;
要是斯泰普顿有些信以为真的话
if Stapleton partly believes it's true
也许他会因此不想让他妹妹嫁给你
perhaps he might want his sister not to be.
是啊 我明白了
Yes I know.
等到这个事情解决了再说吧
Just till the business is resolved.
好的
Yes of course.
我们一起走回去吧
Well shall we walk home together?
赖恩天文台
The Ryan Observatory please.
我会永远为此对你感到抱歉
I am forever in your debt.
噢 根本不必如此
Oh no not at all.
日安
Well good day.
日安 亨利爵士
Good day Sir Henry.
好极了哦
Well well.
发生什么事了?
What happened?
斯泰普顿
Stapleton.
我还是觉得这家伙神经兮兮的
I still think the fellow's crazy
可是他刚刚向我表达了
but he's just given me the most complete apology
我这一辈子能听到的最由衷的歉意了
a man's ever likely received in his life
而且他还邀请我们明天去他那用餐 也就是星期五
and he's invited us to dinner tomorrow, Friday indeed.
好啊 我很想去呢
Good I'll look forward to it.
格林盆的邮局
The post at Grimpen.
正是
Just so.
谢谢 先生
Thank you sir.
我能跟您说句话吗 先生?
May I have a word sir?
当然可以
Of course.
您...您对我们一直很好 先生
You...you've been very good to us sir
我愿意为您效犬马之劳
and I should like to do the best I can for you.
我发现了一件事情 先生
There's something I found out sir.
什么?
Yes?
我们是在聆讯后发现的
We found it after the inquest
我们谁也没告诉 不知该怎么说
hadn't told a mortal soul didn't know how.
是有关查尔斯爵士之死 先生
It's about Sir Charles' death sir.
你知道他是怎么死的吗?
You know how he died?
不 先生
No sir.
那是什么事?
Well what then?
我知道那时他为什么会出现在大门口
I do know why he was at the gate at that hour.
为什么?
Why?
去跟一个女人会面 先生
To meet a woman sir.
女人?
Woman?
你能确定吗?
Are you sure?
噢 是的 先生
Oh yes sir.
那她叫什么?
Well what was her name?
我只能告诉您她名字的缩写
I can only give you her initials sir.
是的 我太太发现了一样东西
Yes there was something my wife found.
她当时正在清洁这个房间
She was cleaning out this very room,
也就是查尔斯爵士的书房
Sir Charles's study sir
就在那边的壁炉里
in the grate there
她发现了一块小纸片
she found this scrap of paper
都烧掉了 爵士
it was all burnt but
不过字迹还可以辨认
well it could still be read.
从反光和笔迹看得出
From the shine and the writing
您知道我的意思吧 先生?
if you know what I mean sir?
是的 我知道 接着说吧
Of course I understand please go on.
她把我叫来 我就把内容写了下来
Well she called to me and I wrote it down.
'请您...
'Please,
您是一位绅士
please as you are a gentleman
请您把这封信烧了
burn this letter
十点钟在大门见'
and be at the gate by ten o'clock.'
落款缩写是 'L.L.'
Then the initials 'L.L.'
下午好 华生医生
Good afternoon Doctor Watson.
弗兰克兰先生?
Mr. Frankland?
上来吧 我替你上杯茶
Come along up I shall order you tea.
谢谢
Thank you.
你到这儿来
You're here to solve
是来解开巴斯克维尔之谜的 对吧?
the Baskerville mystery are you not?
我有个望远镜
Well I have a telescope.
可以看到沼地上的景象
I see things on the moor
你当然是应该有所了解的
surely you should know about them.
这肖像太动人了
This striking portrait.
嗯?
Huh?
罗拉 是你女儿吧 弗兰克兰先生?
Lora, your daughter Mr. Frankland?
是的
Yes.
是我的女儿
Yes that is my daughter.
可现在不是了
The woman she has become is not.
这边走 医生
This way doctor.
怎么回事呢?
How's that?
我剥夺了她的继承权
Disinherited her.
噢 真是令人难过
Oh I'm sorry to hear it.
哼 你知道
You are what do you suppose
她对她爸爸都做了些什么吗?
such a thing does to her father?
这边走
This way.
嫁给了一个骗子 先生
Married her seducer sir.
一个艺术家
An artist,
所谓的艺术家
so called,
不是那种艺术家
not that artist
那种艺术家能挣钱养活自己
that artist earned his living.
她的那个艺术家太伟大了 伟大到无法出去挣钱
Her artist was to grand to earn his living.
艺术家?
Artist?
韦斯特尔 莱茵斯 一个叫莱茵斯的家伙
Wastrel Lyons, fellow called Lyons.
听说过他吗?
Ever heard of him?
没有
No actually.
罗拉 莱茵斯
Lora Lyons.
没人听说过
Nobody has.
他追的是她的钱...其实是我的钱
After her money, my money.
上周在芬尼沃斯他们焚烧了我的肖像
I was burned in effigy in Fernworthy last week.
我记得你曾经预言过会发生这样的事情
You predicted that I remember.
一点没错 因为我知道这里执法机关办事拖拉
Exactly so because I know the slackness of authority here abouts.
我对政府的诉讼案
A case of Frankland v. Regina
将会引起公众的关注
will bring the matter of all the attention to the public.
我告诉过警方
I told the police they would have occasion
他们那样对待我迟早会后悔的
to regret their treatment of me
而我的话现在已经应验了
and already my words have come true.
怎么回事?
How so?
我可以告诉他们一件 他们迫切想知道的事情
I could tell them what they are dying to know.
可你并不打算这样做吧?
But you're not going to?
当然不
Certainly not.
是偷猎之类的事情吗?
Some case of poaching?
偷猎 哼 胡说八道
Poaching fiddlesticks.
是那个逃犯塞尔丹 先生 那个疯狂的刺客
The convict sir, Selden, the mad stabber.
你该不会是说你知道他在哪儿吧?
You don't mean to say you know where he is?
差不多吧
Near enough.
警方从来就没想到
It has never occurred to the police
抓住这个人的最好方法就是
that the way to catch the man
找出他食物的来源
was to find out where he got his food
再顺藤摸瓜去抓他
and so trace it to him.
白瑞摩
Barrymore.
他的食物是由一个小孩送去的
His food is taken to him by a child.
小孩?
A child?
对啊
Why not?
我观察了这孩子一个多星期了
I have observed the child for more than a week.
小孩的本性天真
It is in the nature of children
很容易对错误的对象忠心耿耿
to form perverse allegiances.
但是事情当然更有可能是
But surely it's more likely to be
沼地牧人的儿子
the child of a moorland shepherd
给他父亲送饭罢了
taking him his lunch.
如果是放牧的话 地点是常有变化的
Flocks move.
快点
Quick
华生医生 快点
Doctor Watson quick.
是的 我看到他了
Yes I see him.
摩梯末医生
Dr. Mortimer.
华生医生
Dr. Watson.
我要给你看一件不可思议的东西
I have something marvelous to show you.
美极了 对吧?
Isn't it beautiful?
很漂亮
Splendid.
迄今为止我所找到的 这种头型中最为完整的一个了
The most complete of its kind I've yet found.
又是我自己找到的
I find it myself once more.
今天工人们都不在
The laborers aren't here today.
真是非常漂亮
It is quite, quite beautiful.
如果这世上还有一种我不能容忍的动物的话
If there's one animal on this planet,
那应该就是兔子了
which I cannot abide, it is a rabbit.
为啥?
Really?
兔子老是挖地洞
Rabbit's burrow.
你有没有想过
Have you any conception
一窝兔子
of what a family of rabbits
一夜之间就能对挖掘工作造成的破坏吗?
can do to the chronology of a dig in a single night?
你是要到墓地去 对吧?
You were on your way to Necropolis.
要是你愿意的话 我可以带你去参观
I could show you around if you like.
墓地?
The Necropolis?
很多人认为那是一个新石器时代的村落
Most people think it an in Neolithic village
但是我有理由认为那是一个墓地
but I have reason to believe that a burial ground
有着一些非常有趣的特征
some most interesting features.
很高兴有你陪伴
I shall be glad of your company
那边有人在露营
there someone bivouacked near there.
是谁?
Who is it?
是那个亨利爵士一到这儿
It's the man who has been at Sir Henry's heels
就开始跟踪他的人
since he landed here.
我觉得他心怀不轨
I can't think his motives are benevolent so
所以要是你能来 再带上你擅长使用的那把枪
if you come I shall be obliged
我将感激不尽
if you bring that gun you handle so well.
也许会有危险
There may be some danger.
如果有危险的话
If there's to be danger
两把枪总比一把强
then 2 guns will be better than one.
是的
Yes.
你认识罗拉 莱茵斯吗?
Do you know?
认识 她是老弗兰克兰的女儿
Old Frankland's daughter, yes,
也是我的病人之一
she's a patient of mine.
她住在库柏特斯
She lives in Coombe-Tracey.
你知道他剥夺了她的继承权 一个子儿也不给她吗?
He's cut her off you know without a penny.
你知道她认识查尔斯爵士吗?
Do you know she was acquainted with Sir Charles?
噢 那倒是有可能
Oh it's possible.
她的婚姻出现问题之后
After her marriage went wrong
她开始出去工作
she was able to set up for herself
当打字员挣点薪水
in a small way as a typist.
也许工作是查尔斯爵士帮她找的
Sir Charles may have made that possible.
他为不少慈善事业捐资
He was a man who fostered many good causes.
她也许就是受资助者之一
She may have been one of them.
莱茵斯是怎样的一位画家?
What sort of a painter was Lyons?
噢 才华出众
Oh brilliant.
'华生医生在赖福特庄园'
'Dr. Watson is at Lafter Hall.
也许那位神秘人所跟踪的人
Perhaps it is you
就是你
who's been dogged by this secret man.
而并非亨利爵士
Not Sir Henry at all.
我们该怎么做?
What do we do?
我打算等着
I intend to wait.
灯
Lamp.
真是个美好的夜晚 医生
It's a lovely evening Doctor.
我觉得你到外面来
I really think you would be more comfortable
会比呆在里头更舒服
outside than in.
当我看见一个雪茄烟头
When I see a cigarette stub
牌子是布莱德雷 牛津街
marked Bradley Oxford Street
我知道我的朋友华生就在附近
I know my friend Watson is in the neighborhood.
那枪要小心点哦
Be careful with that gun.
我还以为你在贝克街
I thought you were in Baker Street
忙着那起勒索案呢
working on that case of blackmail?
我就是想让你这样认为
That's what I wished you to think.
你该对我有更好的印象 福尔摩斯
I've deserved better at your hands Holmes.
你利用我又不信任我
You used me and do not trust me.
呃 要是我出现了
Well my presence would have warned
我们的厉害对手就会警惕起来
our very formidable opponents
提防着我们
and put them in our guard.
有必要让你和亨利爵士认为
It was essential that you and Sir Henry
我一直在伦敦
believed me to be in London all the time
那样你们的行为才不会露馅儿
and behaved accordingly.
摩梯末医生
Doctor Mortimer.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
你在德文郡呆了多久了?
How long have you been in Devon?
我来的第二天晚上你就看见我了
Right after you saw me on my second night
当时我真是很蠢
when I was foolish enough
竟然站在月光下
to show myself against the moon.
那我的报告全都白费了?
All of my reports have been wasted.
并非都是白费的
Not all of them you know.
都在这儿呢
Here they are
我向你保证我都认真拜读了
and very well thumbed I assure you.
我还不得不贿赂这里的邮局呢
I had to subvert the local post office.
干得好 亲爱的朋友
Brilliant my dear fellow,
真是太好了
brilliant.
我知道你们肯定有好多事要商谈
You must, I know, have much to discuss
而我也得回家了
and I must be getting home.
我还有个问题 福尔摩斯先生
Please one question Mr. Holmes.
您是不是快发现
Are you any closer to discovering what,
那条所谓的猎犬到底是什么了?
if anything, the hound is?
是的
I am.
它真的存在吗?
Does it exist?
确实存在
It does.
谢谢 摩梯末医生
Thank you Dr. Mortimer.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
日安 华生医生
Good day Doctor Watson.
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your help.
让我看看我能给你点什么吃的
Now let me see what meager refreshment I can provide.
卡怀特 听差所的那个小男孩
Cartwright, the little chap from the express office,
我把他带到这儿来了
I brought him down with me
以满足我简单的日常需要
to look after my simple wants.
一条面包和一条干净的衬领就足够了
A loaf of bread and a clean collar.
我发现有个住在库柏特斯的女人
I've discovered that there's a woman
名字的缩写就是L.L.
Iiving in Coombe-Tracey with the initials L.L.
噢 是的 弗兰克兰的女儿罗拉 莱茵斯
Awe yes Frankland's daughter, Lora Lyons.
我们调查方向一致啊
Our research has been running along the same lines.
你知道
Did you know that she's
她正打算跟她的丈夫离婚吗?
seeking a divorce from her husband?
但她却没有钱来打离婚官司
But she lacks the means to carry it through.
那笔费用可不菲
It is a costly business.
尝尝我的炖菜
Do try my stew.
噢 摩梯末医生认为查尔斯爵士
Awe, now Dr. Mortimer thought that Sir Charles
应该是她背后的捐助人
might have been a discreet benefactor.
是嘛?
Really?
有意思
That's interesting.
吃吧 华生
Please Watson.
很恶心哎 福尔摩斯
Its quite disgusting Holmes.
是的
Yes.
是的  没错
Yes it is.
呃 趁热吃更好吃
Well it's better when it's hot.
你知道吗? 罗拉 莱茵斯
Did you know there was a close intimacy
和那个昆虫学家斯泰普顿
between Lora Lyons
两人关系亲密
and the entomologist, Stapleton?
我不知道
No I did not.
是的 他们私会还相互通信
Yes they meet, they write.
她无疑正指望成为他的太太
She's no doubt counting on becoming his wife.
这是我们手中最有力的武器了
That is the most powerful weapon in our hands.
怎么回事?
How?
我不明白
I don't understand.
因为事实上斯泰普顿小姐
Because Miss Stapleton is in reality
是斯泰普顿的妻子 而不是他妹妹
Stapleton's wife not his sister.
他的妻子?
His wife?
往诺森布兰德旅馆 给我们发来警告的
Yes it was she who sent us that warning
正是她
to the Northumberland Hotel.
为什么要如此精心地欺骗我们呢?
Why this elaborate deception?
别问我细节 华生
Don't ask me the particulars Watson
不过这是一起谋杀
but it is murder.
一起精心策划的冷酷的故意谋杀
Refined, cold-blooded, deliberate murder.
你是怎么得出这个结论的?
What led you to it?
他是一位真正的昆虫学家
He is a genuine entomologist.
但是他唯一的一次声明
But that mention of his sole, claim to fame,
是他发现了兰凯尼迪蝶亚种
his discovery of a subspecies Lycanidi
那对于他来说恰好是致命的证据
that was his fatal moment.
因为一个物种只能有一个发现者
There can only be one discoverer of a species.
这就暴露了他
That pinpointed him.
真是一次很辛苦的追踪...
It has been a hard trail...
快
Quickly.
是亨利爵士
It's Sir Henry.
是塞尔丹
It's Selden.
是亨利爵士的衣服 把这可怜的恶棍送上了西天
Sir Henry's clothes were the poor devils death.
真是个可怜的恶棍
Poor devil indeed.
事实上都不成人样了
There's only a half-life in truth.
暂时不能让任何人知道
No one must know for the moment.
我们必须把尸体藏起来
We must hide the body.
不能让亨利爵士知道这条猎犬的事
Sir Henry must know nothing of hearing the hound.
这样他才会有更好的勇气
He'll have a better nerve
去经受明天的考验
for the ordeal he must undergo tomorrow.
这就是巴斯克维尔庄园了?
So this is Baskerville Hall?
请稍等一会儿
One moment please.
看这是谁?
Who?
是斯泰普顿!
It's Stapleton!
他也是巴斯克维尔家的人
He's a Baskerville.
查尔斯爵士的弟弟
Sir Charles' brother,
在哥斯达黎加死于黄热病的那个
who died of yellow fever in Costa Rica,
他并非没有后裔
did not die childless.
我们逮到他了 华生 我们逮到他了
We have him Watson, we have him.
我发誓 到明天晚上
And I do swear that by tomorrow night
他就会落入我们的网中
he will be fluttering in our net
像他的蝴蝶那样无助地挣扎
as helpless as well as his own butterflies.
华生和我得去伦敦一趟
I feel that Watson and I must go to London.
伦敦?
London?
我觉得在这儿节骨眼上
I think we will be more useful there
我们在那儿会更有用
at this present juncture.
抱歉
Excuse me.
可以给我来杯新鲜的咖啡吗?
Might I have some fresh coffee?
当然了 先生
Certainly sir.
可我还以为
But I thought you were going
你是打算来帮我渡过难关的
to see me through this business?
相信我 亲爱的朋友
Trust me my dear fellow.
我相信
I do.
告诉斯泰普顿
Tell Stapleton that I would have been happy
我本来很乐意陪你一同前往的
to come with you
可是有急事需要我去城里一趟
but the urgent business requires me to be in town.
我不明白
I don't understand
难道我不能跟你们一起去伦敦吗?
should I not come with you to London?
为什么要我单独留下?
Why should I stay here alone?
不行 你必须留下
No you must stay
而且一定要按我说的去做
and do exactly as I tell you.
我当然会
Of course I will.
开车去梅利琵庄园
Drive to Merripit House,
再把车打发回来
send the truck back and let it be known
让大家以为你要步行回家
that you intend to walk home.
穿过沼地吗?
Across the moor?
在晚上?
At night?
如果我对你的胆识和勇气
If I had not every confidence
没有足够的信心的话
in your nerve and courage
我是不会建议你那样做的
I would not suggest it.
你必须得这样做
It is essential that you do this.
我会按你说的做
Then I will do just what you say.
走小路
Take the path.
一定要走从梅利琵庄园 到格林盆大路的那条小路
Exactly on the path from Merripit House
就是你回家通常会走的那条路线
to the Grimpen Road, it is your natural way home.
你们打算什么时候走?
And when do you intend to leave?
早餐后就动身
Immediately after breakfast.
谢谢 白瑞摩
Thank you Barrymore.
不用谢 先生
Sir.
你是莱茵斯太太吗?
Mrs. Lyons?
是的
Yes.
你承认是你要求查尔斯爵士
So you admit that you asked Sir Charles
十点钟在门口见面
to meet you at the gate at ten o'clock
而你却说你没有赴约?
but you say that you did not keep the appointment?
我没去
I did not.
你知道那是他死亡的确切时间吗?
You do realize that was the very hour of his death?
你是在指控我吗 先生?
Is that an accusation sir?
不 不是的
No, no.
我只不过是在问你
I'm merely asking if you can forge a connection
是否能推断出这两者间有什么联系
between the two events.
没有什么联系
There is no connection.
莱茵斯太太  我们认为这是一起谋杀
Mrs. Lyons we believe this to be a case of murder
而证据正指向
and the evidence may implicate
你的朋友斯泰普顿先生
not only your friend Mr. Stapleton
还有他的太太
but his wife as well.
他太太?
His wife?
莱茵斯太太  他所谓的妹妹
Mrs. Lyons the person who has passed for his sister
其实是他的妻子
is really his wife.
他妻子?
His wife?
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes?
斯泰普顿承诺
Mr. Stapleton offered me marriage
如果我能跟我丈夫离婚
on condition that I could obtain a divorce
就会娶我为妻
from my husband.
他告诉我...
He told me...
他怎么能骗我呢!
how he has lied.
他一而再再而三地欺骗我
He has lied and lied and lied.
我干嘛还要真心对他呢?
Why should I preserve faith with him
他根本就没有真心对我!
he never kept any with me?
你们尽管问吧
Ask me what you will.
我不会有任何隐瞒
There is nothing I shall hold back.
你说查尔斯爵士帮你
You have said Sir Charles helped you
当上了专职的打字员
to set yourself up as a professional typist,
大概是在你丈夫弃你而去之后的事吧
presumably that was after your husband deserted you.
是的
Yes.
查尔斯爵士知道我父亲是不会帮我的
Sir Charles knew my father would not help me.
有件事情我得向您发誓
One thing I swear to you,
我写那封信的时候
when I wrote the letter
压根就没想要伤害那位老人
I never dreamed of any harm to the old gentleman
他一直是我最仁慈的朋友
who had been my kindest friend.
我完全相信你 夫人
I entirely believe you madam.
查尔斯爵士是不是请斯泰普顿
And Sir Charles used Stapleton
出面做这件事?
as an intermediary?
因为他不想人们知道他的善行
He did not like to be seen to be doing good.
在查尔斯爵士死亡的当天
And the letter that you sent to Sir Charles
你写给他的那封信呢?
on the day of his death?
我离婚需要钱
I needed money for my divorce.
我听说他要去伦敦了
I had heard he was leaving for London.
寄信的主意是斯泰普顿出的吧?
And the sending of the letter was suggested by Stapleton?
那封信是他口述的
He dictated it.
他的理由是
The reason he gave
查尔斯爵士会帮我
was that Sir Charles would help
支付我离婚所需的诉讼费用
with the legal expenses of my divorce.
是他阻止你去赴约的吗?
And he dissuaded you from keeping the appointment?
还让我发誓一个字也不要说出去
And swore me to silence concerning it.
他说这起死亡
He said that the death
是一起非常神秘的事件
had been a very mysterious one
要是人们知道了事实
and that I should certainly be suspected
我自然会受到怀疑
were the facts to become known.
他吓唬我要我保持沉默
He frightened me into silence.
你差点就犯罪了 莱茵斯太太
A very fortunate escape Mrs. Lyons.
你一直处在危险的边缘
You have been near the edge of the precipice.
学犯罪学的学生们应该记得
Students of criminology will remember
66年在"小俄罗斯"(位于托特汉姆一带 俄罗斯移民聚集地)的格兰德
the incidents in Grodno, in Little Russia,
所发生的那些案件
in the year '66, and of course
当然还有北卡罗莱纳州的安德森谋杀案
there are the Anderson murders in North Carolina,
但这起案件
but this case possesses features
绝对是独一无二
which are entirely its own.
华生医生告诉我你枪法不错
Dr. Watson tells me that you handle a gun.
算是个神枪手吧
I'm a fairly proficient.
嗯 最初是你
Well it was you, who first,
让我们开始注意这起案件的
brought this case to our attention.
案件的高潮怎么能没有你的参与呢?
Isn't it right that you'd be with us at the climax?
谢谢
Thank you.
摩梯末医生和我看守这条小道的时候
While Dr. Mortimer and I guard the path
你负责看着那座房子 华生
you watch the house Watson.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like it.
起雾了
There's fog in the air.
洼地里已经雾蒙蒙了
It's in the hollows already.
小心点 华生
Be careful Watson.
你能来我太高兴了
I'm so pleased you could come.
华生医生得回伦敦去真是太遗憾了
It's a pity Dr. Watson had to return to London.
但是我相信
Nevertheless I'm sure we'll have
我们今晚在一起会过得很愉快的
a pleasant evening together.
抱歉我得离开一会儿 亨利爵士
If you'd excuse me for a moment Sir Henry.
我很快回来
I shant be long.
救命!
Help!
救救我!
Please!
请救救我啊!
Help me Please!
我离开的时候亨利爵士还在屋子里
Sir Henry was still inside the house when I left.
天色越来越暗了
It's getting late.
你是说贝莉 斯泰普顿不在那儿吗?
You said Beryl Stapleton was not there?
不在
No.
我想不出她能在哪儿
I cannot think where she might be
晚餐桌只摆了两个人的位子
and there were only 2 places laid for dinner.
雾气一直在加重
That fog is getting thicker all the time.
鼓起勇气 亨利爵士
Courage Sir Henry.
勇敢些!
Brave it.
来了
It's coming.
你是一个勇敢的人
You're a brave man.
医生
Doctor?
没事的 亨利爵士
It's all right Sir Henry.
没事了
It's all right.
那猎犬窜到我们前头去了
The hound got past us
你要是还撑的住的话
now if you can manage it
我们必须尽快回到那屋子里去
we must get back to the house as soon as possible.
竟然是磷?
Phosphorus?
不
No.
先生 不行
Sir no.
先生
Sir.
我抗议 先生
I protest sir.
先生 你不可以...
Sir you are not allowed.
华生!
Watson?
停下 先生 停下
Stop sir stop.
门锁住了
The door's locked.
救命!
Help!
救救我!
Help me!
救命!
Help!
救我!
Please help!
在里头!
In here!
救命!
Help!
她伤得很重
She's badly hurt.
畜生!
The brute.
你没事了
You're all right.
我以为他爱我
I thought this man loved me.
他什么也不爱!
He loves nothing!
他在哪儿?
Where is he?
警方已...
The police have...
他跑了
He escaped.
他会去沼地中他的那个小岛
He'll go to his island in the mire.
我必须小心
I must take care.
非常小心
Great care.
不
No.
救命
Help me.
有人吗 救我啊!
Please somebody help me!
救命!
Help me!
福尔摩斯确定
Holmes had established that Stapleton
斯泰普顿的这条狗是他从玛格兰仕...
had bought the dog from Mangles of the...
伦敦弗汉姆路的罗斯&玛格兰仕店中买下
Ross and Mangles of the Fulham Road in London.
他带着它沿着德文郡的北线走
He took it on the north Devon line
走了很长的路程
and walked a great distance
穿过沼地到了他的家
over to the moor to his home,
正如我们所知道的
as we know he eventually kenneled it
他最后把它养在格林盆沼地中央
at the heart of the Grimpen Mire.
格林盆沼地
Of the Grimpen Mire.
如果那畜生把亨利爵士撕成碎片
How on earth did he expect
他到底打算怎么
to claim the inheritance if this creature
来宣称他对遗产的继承权呢?
had mauled Sir Henry to death?
撕成碎片 用词很好 华生
Mauled, very good word Watson.
通过一些中间机构
Through intermediaries Baron Stapleton said
巴罗 斯泰普顿说他打算回到中美洲去
that he intended to return to Central America
通过英国政府机构
and conduct his claim upon the estate
确认他是巴斯克维尔家族后人的身份
from the depths of Costa Rica.
再从哥斯达黎加内陆
Having established his identity as a Baskerville
发来他对遗产继承权的声明
through the British authorities there.
当然他对房产是没有什么兴趣的
Of course he had no interest in the estate.
他只不过是想要钱
He simply wanted the money.
靴子的事情又是怎么回事?
What about the boot?
他偷了靴子
He stole the boot presumably
大概是想要亨利爵士衣物中的一件物品
to have an article of Sir Henry's clothes
可以让猎狗以此来追踪他
and to set the hound on him.
这就是为什么新靴子用不上的缘故
That is why the new boot would not do.
亨利爵士没有穿过它
Sir Henry had not worn it.
华生 我们要迟到了
Watson we are late.
我有两张去看"胡格诺派教徒"(歌剧)的票子
I have tickets for Les Huguenots
在卡文嘉顿上演
at Cover Garden.
路上顺便去玛西尼餐厅用点晚餐如何?
A little dinner at Marcini's on the way?
太好了 福尔摩斯
Wonderful Holmes.
卖报 卖报
Paper, paper.
谁要晚报?
Who wants an evening paper?